Guide to the Rob Walker Papers
Department of Special Collections
Rob Walker papers
1982-1995
M0742
Walker, Rob
8 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection contains presentation slides, reports, sales material, and other documentation from from LSI Logic Corp.; articles and papers given by Rob Walker; documents from Fairchild Semiconductor; specifications from Lawrence Livermore Laboratories; and, documentation from Philco Corp.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Rob Walker, 1995 (Accession 1995-030), 1998 (Accession 1998-303), 2003 (Accession 2003-269), and 2005 (Accession 2005-110)
Biography / Administrative History
Walker is an ASIC (Application specific integrated circuits) consultant and founder of LSI Logic. He is also the author of SILICON DESTINY: THE STORY OF ASIC AND LSI LOGIC CORPORATIONS, CMC Publications (Milpitas, Calif.), 1993.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains manuals, binders of research materials, documents, and minutes of meetings from Fairchild Semiconductor; materials documenting Walker's career at LSI Logic, including correspondence, presentation slides, reports, publications put out by the Corporate Communications Department, as well as articles and papers by Rob Walker and by others; technical data from Walker's research at Lawrence Livermore Laboratories in the 1960's; technical manuals, marketing materials, and other documents accumulated during Walker's years at Philco Corp.; and an audiocassette of a 1995 interview with Walker.
Arrangement
Arranged into five series: Series 1: Fairchild Semiconductor materials; Series 2: LSI Logic Corp. materials; Series 3: Lawrence Livermore Laboratory materials; Series 4: Philco Corp. materials; and Series 5: Audiovisual materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Fairchild Camera and Instrument Corporation. Fairchild Semiconductor Division.; LSI Logic Corporation.; Application specific integrated circuits.; Computer industry.; Microelectronics industry--California--Santa Clara County.; Science--History.
Other Index Terms Related to this Collection
The rise of the silicon architect companies: manuscript draft.
Collection Contents
- Fairchild Semiconductor materials, 1966-1972, Series 1
  Series Scope and Content Summary
  This series contains manuals, binders of research materials and documents, articles and papers by Rob Walker, and minutes of Fairchild meetings.
  - Fairchild binder, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fairchild binder, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fairchild binder, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fairchild binder, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fairchild binder, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fairchild binder, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fairchild binder, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fairchild Micro Matrix design handbook, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fairchild Micromatrix handbook, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - FAIRSIM user manual, and, FAIRSIM II user manual, 1968 - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fairchild Semiconductor. Plan ahead for LSI / by Cloyd E. Marvin and Robert Walker, 1967 Jan. 13 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Standard ICS for digital data communication / R.M. Walker and R.A. Aldrich. -- In Electrical Engineer, 1968 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - MSI digital voter provides error detection and correction / Robert M. Walker, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - PPC meeting minutes - Fairchild MOS, 1968 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reunion of Fairchild Micromosaic people, 1981 Feb. 18 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fairchild miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 16)
- LSI Logic Corp. materials, 1982-1994, Series 2
  This series contains materials documenting Rob Walker's career at LSI Logic, and includes correspondence, presentation slides, reports, publications put out by the Corporate Communications Department, as well as articles and papers by Rob Walker and by others.
  - Correspondence and memos, 1981-1990, Subseries 2.1
    Subseries Scope and Content Summary
    This subseries contains correspondence and memos to and from Rob Walker relating to LSI Logic's project, products, and goals.
    - Correspondence re: litigation -- Lear Siegler, Inc. vs. LSI Logic Corp., 1982 Jan. 12 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Memos, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Memos, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Memos, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Memos, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Memos, [1984?] (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Memos, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Memos, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Memos, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Includes extensive memos on LSI's Modular Design Environment.
    - Memos, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Memos, 1990 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Memos, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Presentation materials, 1981-1990, Series 2.2
    This series is almost entirely comprised of photocopies of slide cells for talks that Rob Walker gave while at LSI Logic to both internal and external audiences.
    - Logic array customers foil, 1981 Mar. 25 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Advantages of the phased ILC approach,1981 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - LSI design philosophy, 1981 Nov. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Testing logic arrays: copy of issue to Hellman, et al., 1981 Nov. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Slip of the lip could sink a chip presentation foil, 1981 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - LDSI requires access to the following ....,ca. 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - LSI Logic ECL approach, ca. 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - VTM4 - work stations presentation, ca. 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous presentation foils, ca. 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Off chip driver circuit & I/O voltage levels presentation, 1982 Feb. 13 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Design partners & ECL product plans, 1982 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - LSI Logic Corp. approach to arrays, 1982 Mar. 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - High performance, bipolar array (HBA) presentation, 1982 Mar. 3 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Engineering status presentation, 1982 May 18 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - AMD presentation / Rob Walker & Dan Wong, 1982 June 24 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - ECL arrays, 1982 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - July flash & August forecast, 1982 Aug. 3 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - VTM1.LDS1 test foils, 1982 Oct. 11 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - New CAD tools, 1982 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Logic arrays presentation, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous CMOS & Macrocell foils, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Chip size presentation, ca. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Comparison of gate arrays & standard cell approaches to user-defined VLSI, ca. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Design interface IIA, IIE, & III presentations, ca. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Pad limited designs presentation, ca. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - VTM3 digital foils, ca. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Customer visibility and control, 1983 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - LDSI - LSI 5 k enhancements, 1983 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Macrocell application presentation, 1983 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Technological leadership presentation, 1983 Feb. 9 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - LSI Logic ECL approach presentation, 1983 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Market presentation, ca. 1983 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - MPI / LSI logic relationships, ca. 1983 Feb. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Benchmark presentation, 1983 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Layout related CAD development, 1983 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Monthly status report presentation, ca. 1983 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - LDS presentation, ca. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - VTM5 CAD tools presentation, ca. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1984 engineering plan presentation, ca. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Silicon structures management review presentation, 1984 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Ericcson meeting presentation, 1984 Jan. or Feb. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - LSI Logic application specific IC families presentation, 1984 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - IC benchmark presentation, 1984 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Star project review presentation, 1984 June 26 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Review of engineering operations Q2 / Q3, 1984 July 17 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Toshiba SOS 7840 presentation, 1984 Aug. 27 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Logic array design presentation, 1984 Sept. 13 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Norden / LSI Logic meeting presentation, 1984 Sept. 19 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Toshiba presentation, 1984 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Engineering quarterly meeting presentation, 1984 Oct. 22 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Design accuracy, 1984 Oct. 22 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous presentations, 1984 Oct. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Gate array benchmark presentation, 1984 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - LSI Logic Corp. [end of year presentation], 1984 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - LDS approach, 1985 Nov. 15 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Compiler presentation, 1985 Dec. 4 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - LSI Logic Corp. MACGEN presentation, 1986 Jan. 10 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Year of computer revolution presentation, 1986 Feb. 11 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Structured compiler presentation, 1986 Apr. 10 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Modern 32-bit workstations exhibit, 1986 May 30 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Projects presentation, 1986 May 30 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - LSI Logic presentation to the Department of Defense, National Security Agency, and Central Intelligence Agency, 1986 June (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Systems Research Laboratory presentation, 1986 July (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Radiation hardened arrays presentation, 1986 July 17 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Classic silicon compilers - a failure, 1986 Aug. 4 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - LSI Design System (LDS 1) foils, 1986 Aug. 4 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Cell design at LSI Logic presentation, 1986 Aug. 7 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Sequent status presentation, 1986 Aug. 26 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Crush presentation, 1986 Aug. 31 & Sept. 2 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Flexible interface presentation, 1986 Sept. 2 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - LSI design environment presentation, 1986 Oct. 22 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - LDS design environment presentation, 1986 Nov. 25 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Steak presentation, 1986 Nov. 26 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - LDS system and modular design presentation, 1987 Mar. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Computers & semiconductors: a battle of survival presentation, 1989 Nov. 27 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - ASIC test - a status report, 1990 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - AMD / LSI engineering issues presentation, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - ASIC supplier presentation, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - CAE workstations presentation, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - CMOS presentation, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous CMOS presentations, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - DC parametrics test input, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - LDSI functional outline, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Lies people tell: LSI ...., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - LSI design philosophy, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Equivalent gates for PLAS, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Macrocell / macrofunction concept, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Rob's overview & extra foils, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Why call it a development system?, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Slides, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Corporate communications materials, 1980-1991, Series 2.3
    This subseries contains reports, publications, press releases, and other documents put out by the Corporate Communications Department of LSI Logic.
    - LSI business plan, 1980 Nov. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - LSI business principles: proposed, ca. 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Board of Directors meeting, 1981 June 23 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - LSI Logic Corp. notice of annual meeting of stockholders, 1991 May 9 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Annual report, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Annual report, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Quarterly reports, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Quarterly reports, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - LSI Logic Corp. consolidated financial settlements, 1982 Dec. 31 and 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Employee handbook, 1987 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Celebrating LSI Logic's first decade, 1981 - 1991, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - LSI Logic Corp. news / investment update, 1986 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - LSI Logic Corp. news / investment update, 1987 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Organization chart, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Press releases, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - LSI Logic Corp. 5-year plan presentation, 1985 Oct. 11 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Logically speaking: a newsletter for the employees of LSI Logic Corp., Vol. 1, no. 1 - ,1984 Dec. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Reports, 1981-1984, Subseries 2.4
    This subseries contains reports generated by LSI Logic Corp.
    - CMOS macrocell library. -- Rev. 1, 1981 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - CMOS macrocell and macrofunction library. -- Rev. 2, 1982 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Engineering Q2 / Q3 report, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - ISAS status reports, 1983 - 1984 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Untitled report [1 of 2], 1982 June (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Untitled report [2 of 2], 1982 June (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Untitled partial report on founding of LSI, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Untitled partial report re: CAD, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Automatic fault generation subsystem - generated faults, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Research and development files, 1982 - 1986, n.d., Subseries 2.5
    This subseries contains technical information and specifications produced by LSI Logic Corp. in its research and development.
    - An OPUS: technical info, 1986 Dec. 12 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Includes computer code and circuit diagrams.
    - MIO Macrocell logic element, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Includes circuit diagrams.
    - Series 7000 2 micron CMOS macrocell arrays, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - SKELISIM code, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 3-bit up-down counter: technical information, 1986 Dec. 9 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Circuit photograph, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Sales and marketing materials, 1983 - 1989, Subseries 2.6
    This subseries contains sales and marketing materials generated by LSI Logic Corp.
    - Product brochures, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Short form catalog, 1988 Nov. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Various data sheets, etc., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - LSI Logic sales update ASIC ASAP new product primer [1 of 3], 1987 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - LSI Logic sales update ASIC ASAP new product primer [2 of 3], 1987 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - LSI Logic sales update ASIC ASAP new product primer [3 of 3], 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - ECL array sales bits, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - SPARCstation and LSI Logic, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Proposal to Digital Equipment Corporation, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Customer survey, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Semicustom LSI vendor survey, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Note: "Confidential" stamped on front of document.
  - Papers and articles by Rob Walker, 1981-1994, Subseries 2.7
    This subseries contains papers and articles written by Rob Walker while at LSI Logic Corp.
    - LSI gate arrays outpace standard logic / Robert Hartmann & Rob Walker, 1981 Mar. 5 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Logic arrays, technologies, and design / Rob Walker, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Converting SSI/MSI and PLA designs to CMOS logic arrays / Rob Walker, Richard Derickson, & Keith R. Lobo, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Partitioning systems into logic arrays / Rob Walker, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - A systems approach to logic arrays / Rob Walker & Don Snoderman, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Logic design for CMOS logic arrays / Rob Walker & Richard Derickson, 1983 Feb. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Gate arrays and standard cell / Rob Walker, 1983 Mar. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - LSIM / ZSIM paper / Rob Walker, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Technology upstarts rock ASIC market / Rob Walker. -- In Electronic Engineering Times, 1994 Nov. 14 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - ASIC test / Rob Walker, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Gate arrays - custom VLSI that is available now / Rob Walker, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - LDS-III multi-array design system / Rob Walker & James S. Koford, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Reflections from product planning / Rob Walker, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Untitled manuscript / Rob Walker, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Figures from unidentified article / Rob Walker, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Papers and articles by other LSI employees, 1981, Subseries 2.8
    This subseries contains papers and articles written by colleagues of Rob Walker at LSI Logic Corp.
    - Current trends and future capability of LSI / W.J. Corrigan, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - A design example - programmable digital audio frequency synthesizer / by Richard Derickson, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - A development system for logic arrays / James S. Koford and Edwin R. Jones, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Articles and clippings about LSI, 1981-1994, Subseries 2.9
    This subseries contains articles and clippings from newspapers, magazines, and other publications LSI Logic Corp.
    - Articles and clippings, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Articles and clippings, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Training materials, n.d. n.d., Subseries 2.10
    This subseries contains training materials generated by LSI Logic Corp.
    - LSI Logic training course: agenda, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Kiet agreement, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Biographical information, n.d., Subseries 2.11
    This subseries contains biographical information about Rob Walker that LSI Logic Corp. included in its publications and corporate documents.
    - Biographical information, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Rob Walker biography, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d., Subseries 2.12
    This subseries contains miscellaneous materials generated by LSI Logic Corp.
    - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - New York resolutions, ca. 1986 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Lawrence Livermore Laboratories materials, 1958-1963, Series 3
  This series contains technical data and reports on various circuit-design projects.
  - Read out for 256 PHA, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Thyratron used as combination gate, storage, and driver for punched paper-tape output / Robert M. Walker, 1959 July 27 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 3D analzyer readout, PHA recordings and Min-Max selector, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Recording system, analog-to-digital convertor, 100-channel commutator specifications, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Digital data procedures / Logic module, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Gate flip flop, two channel P.C. card core monitor Astron resistence measurement system, 1962 - 1963 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Resistence measurement system, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - A handbook of selected semiconductor circuits / prepared by Transistor Applications, Inc. for Bureau of Ships, Dept. of the Navy. -- Washington, D.C.: U.S. Government Printing Office, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Philco Ford materials, 1963-1968, Series 4
  This series contains technical manuals, marketing materials, and other documents generated by Philco Corp. It also contains a copy of the manuscript and the final published version of an article written by Rob Walker entitled: "A building block approach to digital-to-analog convertors".
  - System 4-D maintenance. Model 701 logic module test (WDL-TS-58A). -- Palo Alto, Calif.: Philco. WDL Division, 1966 Jan., WDL HB1050 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - System 4-D digital logic building blocks. -- Palo Alto, Calif.: Philco. WDL Division [1 of 2], 1966 Apr. 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - System 4-D digital logic building blocks. -- Palo Alto, Calif.: Philco. WDL Division [2 of 2], 1966 Apr. 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Optimized microelectronics packaging configuration. -- Palo Alto, Calif.: Philco. WDL Division, 1965 Apr. 2, WDL-TP1860 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Phase 1 report Gemini terminal landing system data subsystem A201.BADA. -- Palo Alto, Calif.: Philco. WDL Division, 1965 Dec. 23 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Mark II Avionics Systems. -- Rev. to Part III, section 3. -- Palo Alto, Calif.: Philco. WDL Division, 1966 July 8, WDL-TP21866A (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - A building block approach to digital-to-analog convertors / Rob Walker. -- In The Electronic Engineer, 1968 May (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - A building block approach to analog convertors, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Philco Logic module tester, model 701, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Philco micromodules short term catalog, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Micromodules, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Philco to design Apollo control center: advertisement. -- In Aviation Week & Space Technology, 1963 June 17 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Philco to design Apollo control center: advertisement. -- In Aviation Week & Space Technology, 1963 June 17 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Audiovisual materials, 1995 May 31, Series 5
  This series contains the audiocassette tape of an interview with Rob Walker done on May 31, 1995.
  - Rob Walker interview on KALW, 1995 May 31, 1 audiocassette (Folder 1)